fender.com 2016-06-08

# Privacy Policy | Fender Musical Instruments

UPDATED NOVEMBER 24TH, 2014

Fender understands your concerns about privacy. So, we want you to understand what types of information we collect on this site and what may happen to that information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should contact us at:

Fender Musical Instruments Corporation  
Attn: Legal  
17600 N. Perimeter Drive, Suite 100  
Scottsdale, AZ 85255  
Last update: 08/07/2013  

November 24th, 2014: Added section 10 - Do Not Track

Fender Musical Instruments Corporation and all of its U.S. and foreign subsidiaries and affiliates (“Fender” or “us” or “we”) take seriously the confidentiality of your personal information. The following Privacy Policy sets forth our information gathering and dissemination practices for Fender.

#### 1\. Agreement to Privacy Policy

BY ACCESSING OR USING THIS WEBSITE, YOU HEREBY AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION AS DISCUSSED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT ACCESS THIS WEBSITE.

#### 2\. Amendments to Privacy Policy

Fender reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Notice of changes to this Privacy Policy will be communicated to you in advance. All changes will be effective immediately upon their posting to this website. Material changes will be conspicuously posted on this website. You agree that by accessing or using the Fender website without any objection following posting of such changes, constitutes your acceptance of the revised terms.

#### 3\. Information We Collect

A. Personally Identifiable Information

Fender may collect information you voluntarily share with us, including any content, record, or electronic communication of any kind, including without limitation your (1) contact information, (2) financial information, (3) demographic information, and (4) other personal information, subject to applicable laws and the terms of this Privacy Policy.

You are not required to provide personally identifiable information in order to visit any Fender website. You must, however, register and provide personally identifiable information in order to access certain portions of the website, be placed on Fender's E-News Service List, join the Fender Community and to enter contests and other promotions.

Fender may use content you provide us through emails, responses to polls, contests or sweepstakes or any other promotional activity. Please be advised that any such submissions become the property of Fender and may be used by Fender for any lawful purpose, subject to applicable law. Fender can edit, rewrite, use, and reuse the content of your submissions, including your name, likeness, photograph, and biographical information in any way and in any media whether now known or invented in the future, with or without attribution, including publication in online publications, and in trade media, and advertising. You agree that any content you send us will not violate any rights of any third-party and that you will only send us content for which you own the rights.

B. Non-Personally Identifiable Information

Fender also collects other information that is not personally identifiable to you, but results solely from your visit to our website. For example, we may collect Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses. We may use web beacons and cookies, which may be placed on your computer when you access the website.

a. IP Addresses

Your Internet Protocol ("IP") address is usually associated with the place from which you enter the Internet, like your Internet Service Provider, your company or your university. By collecting your IP address, Fender's server may record the referring page that linked you to the Fender website (e.g., another website or a search engine), the pages you visit on this website, the website you visit after this website, the ads you see or click on, other information about the type of web browser, computer, platform, related software and settings you are using, any search terms you have entered on this website or a referral website, and other web usage activity and data logged by our web servers. Fender may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, gather broad demographic and geographic information, and administer our website. Fender may also link this information with your personally identifiable information when Fender feels that it is necessary to enforce compliance with its rules and policies, terms of service, or to protect its website, customers or others.

b. Web Beacons

Web beacons are Internet tools, such as transparent images on a website or in e-mails that we may send you, that help us to determine, for instance, whether a page has been viewed or an e-mail opened. For example, when you ask us to send you information on a promotion or newsletter, we may use web beacons to determine how many of the e-mails we sent were actually opened. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including a banner ad, can contain a web beacon.

c. Cookies

Fender may use cookies to track the use of its website and to facilitate and enhance your experience. “Cookies” are small pieces of electronic data that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. The cookies enable Fender to facilitate access to different aspects of the website. For example, by showing when and how you and others visit its website, cookies help Fender to see which pages of the website are popular and which are not. Cookies can also help Fender to improve your enjoyment of this website, for example, by remembering your address or other personal information when you request information or services on the website. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can disable this function so that your browser will not accept cookies. Please be aware that disabling this function may impact your use and enjoyment of this website.

d. Google AdWords Remarketing

Fender use Google AdWords Remarketing to advertise Fender products across the Internet. AdWords Remarketing will display relevant ads tailored to you based on what parts of the Fender website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your machine. THIS COOKIE DOES NOT IDENTIFY YOU OR GIVE ACCESS TO YOUR COMPUTER. The cookie is used to say "This person visited this page, so show them ads relating to that page." AdWords Remarketing allows Fender to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and only display ads that are relevant to you. How to Opt Out of Remarketing and Advertising: If you do not wish to participate in our AdWords Remarketing, you can opt out by visiting Google's Ads Preferences Manager. 

#### 4\. How We Use Your Information

Fender does not sell, rent or loan any of your personally identifiable information to any third party.

Fender may, however, use and share information with third-party suppliers specifically involved in the processing of your information received via the Fender website. Fender may also share your information with our foreign and domestic affiliates and subsidiaries and third-party suppliers, which may require sending your personal information to or from the United States and another country.

Fender will use your personally identifiable information only for the purpose of communicating to you as set forth in this Privacy Policy and any other purpose for which you disclose it to us. If you wish for us to cease use of your personally identifiable information in any way, you may contact us at any time as set forth below. We will contact you in writing via email prior to using your information for any reason other than for the reason you disclosed it to us.

In addition, Fender may use and share aggregated information that does not uniquely identify you when it enables Fender to improve and enrich our services and website content.

Fender reserves the right to use and share your information where such disclosure may be required by law.

#### 5\. Access by Children

This website is not intended for use by children age under age 16. No one under age 16 is allowed to provide any personally identifiable information or use Fender public discussion areas, forums and chats or participate in any contests or any other promotional activities, and Fender does not knowingly collect or use information from children under age 16 through this website.

To subscribe to newsletters and to participate in other activities where personal information is divulged on this website, you must be age 16 or older. Minors under the age of 18 should get the permission of their parent(s) or legal guardian(s) before subscribing to anything on this website.

#### 6\. Choice/Opt-Out

If you are registered to receive Fender's E-News Service List, you may also receive commercial email regarding upcoming Fender promotions and events. If you receive Fender's commercial email and would like to avoid receiving such email in the future, you may opt-out of receiving it by clicking on the opt-out area within that email or by clicking here. Fender will only communicate with you according to your instructions.

#### 7\. Security

Fender limits third party access to personally identifiable information collected on this website. This website has security measures in place that we believe are reasonable to help protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under Fender's control. While Fender cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, Fender uses industry standards, such as Secure Socket Layers (“SSL”) technology, to help safeguard against such occurrences. In certain instances, the information passed between your browser and the Fender system is encrypted with SSL technology to create a protected connection between you and this website to ensure confidentiality. In the event that a breach into the Fender security systems occurs and there is a possibility that an unauthorized person acquires your personal information, Fender will notify you of such a breach under applicable law.

#### 8\. Access to Your Personal Information

If you wish to have access to your personally identifiable information, please contact us with your request. You may also request that Fender update your personal information or correct any factual errors that you believe may exist regarding this information. In the event of a change in control of Fender or sale by Fender of substantially all of its assets, any information owned by or in the control of Fender may be transferred to such Fender successor, who will comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

#### 9\. Third-Party Websites

This website may link to, or be linked to, other websites not maintained by or related to Fender. Fender is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third parties or third-party websites, including any third-party linked or linking websites. To the extent that you disclose personally identifiable information to any such third parties, different rules may apply to their use and disclosure of personal information that you disclose to them. Fender encourages you to review the privacy policies of such websites before disclosing your personal information to them.

#### 10\. Do Not Track

We will automatically collect cookies and other non-personally identifying information when you visit this site. Due to this automatic collection, we do not currently honor do not track requests. We also currently do not participate in any online ad network that tracks users across websites and over time.

#### 11\. Contacting Us

Your privacy is important to Fender. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Fender Musical Instruments Corporation  
Attn: Legal  
17600 N. Perimeter Drive, Suite 100  
Scottsdale, AZ 85255
